<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="https://til.softinio.com/xml/base.min.xml"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>github on Salar Rahmanian: Today I Learned | TIL</title><link>https://til.softinio.com/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in github on Salar Rahmanian: Today I Learned | TIL</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 16:45:33 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://til.softinio.com/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuring Github Pages With a Custom Domain</title><link>https://til.softinio.com/tils/configuring-github-pages-with-a-custom-domain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 16:45:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://til.softinio.com/tils/configuring-github-pages-with-a-custom-domain/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I setup my TIL website and as its a static generated site using &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> I decided to use github pages to host it and use a custom domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To setup my custom domain I went through the following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Verify Domain:&lt;/em> I followed &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/verifying-your-custom-domain-for-github-pages">these steps&lt;/a> to verify. Note that this was done using my GitHub accounts settings and not the repositories settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Configuring my subdomain:&lt;/em> Next I configured my subdomain to be used as my custom domain with GitHub pages by following &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/managing-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site#configuring-a-subdomain">these steps&lt;/a> which involved adding a CNAME record to my DNS settings with my domain registrar. Note that as I was using a subdomain adding a CNAME record was all that was needed (however if I was to use an apex domain, I would have needed to add A and AAAA records too pointing to GitHub&amp;rsquo;s ip addresses).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Add CNAME file:&lt;/em> You need to add a file called &lt;code>CNAME&lt;/code> to the root of your generated static site that contains your host name only (i.e. for this site &lt;code>til.softinio&lt;/code>). As I use Hugo, I put this in the &lt;code>static&lt;/code> directory as when the site is created it will be put in the root. Here is an &lt;a href="https://github.com/softinio/til/blob/main/static/CNAME">example&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;em>Configuring GitHub Pages:&lt;/em> Go to your repositories settings and select pages. Enter your domain name, save it and click check. Tick the box to enforce &lt;code>https&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="notes">Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This TIL does not cover setting up GitHub actions to build and deploy your code. Here is a &lt;a href="https://github.com/softinio/til/tree/main/.github/workflows">sample&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You need to have your site deployed at least once so that the &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> branch is created so that you can set the site source branch in your repositories pages settings.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To make sure your GitHub actions is able to create the &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> branch, go to your repositories settings, then click &lt;code>Actions&lt;/code> then &lt;code>General&lt;/code> and under the &lt;code>workflow permissions&lt;/code> section make sure the &lt;code>read and write permissions&lt;/code> is selected and saved.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/">Hugo Documentation for hosting on GitHub&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>